# MARK PUSTEJOVSKY

11875 CR 4026, Kemp, TX 75143 (469) 820-4098

mpustejovsky@yahoo.com

I have many years of experience with electrical power equipment from 230kV down to 24 volt control circuits. I have experience with design, hands on testing, and training others to perform these roles. I have worked in power plants on protective relay circuits throughout my career, and have been on many emergency calls (and spent many long nights) troubleshoot why a generator, pump, AVR, or other tripped off line. I can help make your facility more reliable and help improve unit availability. I can help make sound engineering decisions on plant upgrades, and manage upgrade projects to be on-time and within budget. I would want to be part of the electrical safety team, and help make the workplace a safe place.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### JAN 2015-FEB 2020

## **VP OF WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT, SHERMCO INDUSTRIES, INC.**

Responsible for development of training, standards, and leadership. Also responsible for implementation of training for a mobile electrical workforce and determine cost effective methods to implement. These included hands on classes, on-line, YouTube type training, social learning and much more. I was also responsible for the development of electrical safety requirements for the workforce and implementing training for employees that work in high risk electrical equipment on a daily basis.

#### **JAN 2010-JAN 2015**

### **DIRECTOR OF ESD PRODUCTION, SHERMCO INDUSTRIES, INC.**

In this role I was over the production groups for engineering services at Shermco within the US. This included field service personnel that perform NETA electrical testing, breaker shop personnel that rebuilt electrical breakers, and all engineering staff. In this role I developed standard operating procedures (SOPs) to coordinate how all offices perform work. SOPs were also key when new companies were acquired so all production personal performed work under the same procedures and methods.

#### **AUGUST 2002-JAN 2010**

#### **ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING MANAGER, SHERMCO INDUSTRIES, INC.**

Development of electrical engineering department for within Shermco. The department focused on engineering studies including arc flash, device coordination, short circuit, power factor correction, and load flow. Also developed a P&C group within engineering to perform relay testing and NERC PRC-005 testing in power plants and utility environments. This group grew from a \$200k support group for Shermco Field Service operations to a \$6M+ production department.

FEB 2000 -AUGUST 2002

FACILITY ELECTRICAL ENGINEER, ATMEL CORP

ATMEL is a semiconductor manufacture and I was responsible for all electrical equipment at the site. The site included a 138kV sub distributed down to twenty four 480V subs that fed the fab equipment. Including UPS equipment.

# **EDUCATION**

**MAY 1993** 

**ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY, TEXAS A&M** 

# **SKILLS**

- Design and Troubleshooting Control and Protective Relay Circuits
- Preventative Maintenance of Electrical Equipment including Transformers, relays, breakers, UPS, batteries, and switchgear.
- Electrical Safety and development of safety programs.
- Project Management
- Leadership and working with people